welcome back we're in conversation with
SNR rain CIO of Isis here Pro AMC uh you
know in the first segment you kind of
heard Narayan layout is a solid
fundamental sort of top-down setup in
terms of how he sees things panning out
in 23 let's get specific now you know
large caps mid cap small caps sectoral
preference dislikes even then uh thanks
for being with us large caps versus the
rest of the Caps mid cap small caps you
like large caps because they offer
valuation Comfort I believe right see
basically what has happened this year is
the bulk of the selling see you know
once you have selling Market corrects
then valuations become cheap let's look
at where they were selling this year it
happened by FIS right where did their
fire sell they sold in large caps right
so large caps became the area where bulk
of the selling has happened this year so
large caps became the area where
valuation Comfort is there to a higher
extent mid cap and small cap the mutual
fund industry ensured that there was
continuous ships right so that area has
seen virtually no selling right so those
areas the valuations you also in the
past famous for calling out a segment
which is looking frothy is it looking
frothy they're looking clearly costlier
than large caps okay because see you
need some wave of selling okay for the
valuations to correct okay and there has
been no way of selling for years now
right so and Retail was also positive so
that's not an area where we have seen
any selling once you see selling the
sectors valuations correct right so
that's why we prefer large gaps over mid
caps and small caps we also like flexi
caps because what happens in flexi caps
is at some point of time when you want
to invest in mid and small because mid
and small are structural areas correct
so at that point of time you can
actually buy mid and small cap ons right
right that's how we look here uh and one
area in the large cap space which is
corrected a lot we spoke about it
earlier as well is I.T Services right
yeah uh one big sector which is down
significantly still uh you you still
like that you see our view is very
simple both the expert oriented sectors
whether it is it and Pharma both have
done very badly in the last one year if
you look thematically those are the two
sectors which have done very badly we
think that both these sectors are worth
systematically investing over the next
one year because uh there is possibility
of global recession so you invest into
the recession you normally make money
just like you know people who invested
in banking into all the banking problems
problem problems maybe a lot of money
yeah something similar so by it fund or
uh yeah you can buy even an exports fund
which covers both right or you can buy a
separate it fund technology fund
separate Health Care fund Pharma fund
one here's about it Pharma is I I
sometimes feel even more although price
damage may not be as much as I I T but
Pharma is kind of completely uh unloved
right now so you know it's it's in
theory theoretically what you said were
very very sweet words you know unloved
sectors
and uh we have always seen any unload
sector automatically means you find that
you can eventually you make a lot of
money and it's not just export oriented
Pharma you like local Indian uh both
because they all had this covet base
right and after the covet base because
of the covet base their next year turned
out to be very bad right so again so the
sector turned out to have two benefits
right one the covet base resulted in a
problem right and the second is export
right so I think you and uh apparently
there are companies uh they already had
an overdose of FDA inspection as well
right so I think between all these
reasons I think these two sectors you
can look at it either through the export
route or separately both Pharma and
Technology right these are very
interesting systematic investing routes
for today the other area is consumer
which you like quite a bit right and
what in consumer because it's a very
wide see there no actually valuations
never correct so we believe that
consumption is a theme is a very
interesting theme but the problem is
that the sector doesn't correct but we
think that one should look look at the
team structurally over the next few
years for which some sectors I mean
within because
broadly it's best to look at the total
theme because when you invest in the
theme today immediately maybe it's best
to invest in sectors like uh Pharma
within the theme or Telecom within the
team or something like that consumer
durables have been doing badly Otto has
been doing badly so those are the themes
which you will invest in now later when
fmcg corrects or consumer durable
correct or retailing correct you'll
invest in those sectors at that point of
time so it's better to invest in a
broader theme because one thing if you
think of a decade ahead it's one of the
themes it is bound to do well because
there is no way in which you can you're
going to have a consumption will not
grow yeah so exporters it Pharma and
basket of sort of consumer consumption
names right one of the other ways we are
actually telling people to do is uh you
know macro investing is going to play a
lot of role over the next one decade
okay in fact our view has been that it
is the Fed which controls everything in
the world so we actually pioneered this
business cycle fund with a launch in
2021 and now every every fund house is
also launched it right we think that
top-down investing has a long road
because just imagine if the FED comes
and says I'm going to cut rates imagine
what kind of a bull market gets created
correct so we think that macro investing
through the business cycle route is
another very good thematic way to
continuously invest for the next decade
because it is finally macro which plays
a role right right any of us expect that
U.S markets will do badly it was a Fed
which brought down the U.S markets yeah
yeah it will be the U.S fed which
actually again is going to take the U.S
markets up or in all the growth stocks
up okay so I think macro investing is
going to be a very very important thing
element to investing over the next
decade okay uh you know the other area
which just you know frenzied movies this
entire PSU Bank space so I want to start
there and then come to private Banks any
interest any uh idea whether this could
continue in your opinion so it's a very
tough call you know viewer some of the
people who actually in many of the funds
which I run we made lot of money out of
PSU of most of the time when we invested
people asked us will you ever make money
in PSU stocks after they have run up no
when people ask me this question I don't
know how to answer them because
tactically they look very good but you
should ask you know in 2020 the number
of questions we were asked why are you
buying why do you have PSU as your top
holding right even today where I have a
PSU as my top holding in some of my
stock funds that I run top holding and
most of the time including some of the
younger people in my company they asked
me how can you have a PSU as a top
holding in your stock right and have all
done so well and have to answer my
younger colleagues in my company I have
to answer Distributors I have to answer
investors and when they do well people
ask me will they continue
now you don't answer the question what
do you think it's kind of they run up
right quite a bit so so the point is you
know we are essentially I am essentially
a contrarian right so when something
does very well right I you know uh six
months back or nine months back when
metals did very well people asked me
would you buy metals from them no I'll
buy the user of metal right so I'm not
trained to give bullish call on
something which is done very well I am
something which people believe is
neglected like for example dead today
right right or taken Pharma today right
but I'm not trained to give bullish call
on something which is done very well
I think is a structural story
they want to perform some other PSU
Banks now correct exactly so you know as
long as interest rates are as long as
demand for credit is going up the near
term looks good in the medium term there
can be some challenges so I tell people
that the short term and long term is
very good right medium term has some
challenges okay you mentioned briefly
Metals right when you last on you said
yeah don't buy producers but by
consumers is that still the way you
located or is reverse now see metals
have corrected a lot and you know if
there's a good big China reopening it
becomes a tactical trade after the
correction but that could be now right
it could be now so structurally I think
tactically it's a interesting sector to
look at okay
steel non-steal the entire both both
actually and unlike uh six to nine
months back there's no frenzy in the
sector no one talks about it correct so
that's how we look at it so it's but is
there 2020 to 22 moves in the sector
unlikely unlikely right right
because that defense is another area
it's a new Earth kind of thing although
BL has been around for years but now
they've got so many other companies
right in different facets of defense do
you own any of these names do you like
them yeah we do own a few of them and
again it's part of the same PSU answer
the question there is some question your
ask me at a 52 week high after 100 move
right I will tell you I will think about
it but you're not pairing uh you're not
pulling back or I mean that could be it
is it's not that the position the sector
being what it is it's never a very big
part of the portfolio the smallest model
these are all smaller parts you know is
it necessary to walk out of a small
position is a question my colleagues and
I discuss about right but do you
actually easily get in and say after a
big mood you want to take a big position
it's not part of my mindset but my
growth oriented investor colleagues they
think about it do you grow the oriented
colleagues think about New Age companies
you know you know there no I actually
moderated many of my colleagues and uh
you brought them around to your way of
thinking I actually told them you have
to take tactically smaller positions and
it helped us a lot right if you look at
it in the last one year yeah the fact
that you know people the old fogies like
me ensured that we took smaller
positions helped us a lot because many
of them corrected 50 60 percent and now
we told them look at everything with an
open mind okay and if you look at it
some of those new age companies we would
have our highest ever position today
after a 50 fall not one year back which
one
implied assumptions on all of them is
much lower than what it was on the day
of the IPO okay okay in some of them
okay uh anything else which which kind
of catches your attention again the
unloved part of the market is what you
like to look at what else is unloved see
I think you know
we were worried about the new age
companies whether people were going
overboard no people have to ask whether
they are going overboard in some of the
smaller and mid caps but in the broader
Market I think the risk of them making
mistakes are lower now
than a year back but in the small and
mid cap people have to do simple
questions what is the trailing price to
earnings what is the trailing price to
go these are the two questions I tell
people to ask as long as they have that
answer to that question they are
comfortable they don't need to do any
big analysis and if there is a good
dividend deal these are the three
questions I tell people to ask and in
this kind of an environment it's
unlikely that multiples will expand
meaningfully yeah that's unlikely when
interest rates are going up right so
earnings have to do the heavy lifting
yeah so uh so so in in that context
anything else that uh any sectors or is
it very stock specific now I mean very
stock specific no but we would be more
uncomfortable with big Borrowers
I'm not talking of banks here because
banks have a lending function and we
would be more comfortable with the cash
Rich cash flow oriented companies right
than with big borrowers not in any other
uh themes that you want to look at any
kind of Ideal consumer users versus
producers anything like that which would
like like or avoid no to summarize what
I would like to say is that people
should believe that mutual funds also
are a vehicle to invest in debt they
should continue to practice asset
allocation anyone who practiced asset
allocation benefited in 2023 and 22 they
will continue to benefit in 2023 by
doing either multi-asset or asset
allocation and do logical investing
don't get carried away in Euphoria and I
believe that it is not yet time to
actually press the accelerator and take
big risks that time will come and when
that time comes and if we get it right
we didn't get it right in June but if we
get it right we will tell you in March
2020 and April 2020 we were very clear
and we did communicate but in June 2022
we were not that clear but we still
believe we are in that middle of the
road path and that's what we think we
are in
but Indian macro has been beautifully
handled India is a fantastic structural
story but against that we have record
valuations and that's the challenge
absolutely it's a pleasure great to
speak with you wish all your viewers are
very happy 2020. thank you so much and
all of you thank you at CNBC